最初  宇宙是一片黑暗
In the beginning, there was darkness,
紧接着一声巨响  混沌初开
and then, bang, giving birth
时间  空间和物质
to an endless, expanding existence of time,
开始不断膨胀
space and matter.
彗星撞击木星
每天
Every day,
我们都在解密这神秘莫测
new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
新发现的行星
令人疯狂的极端之地
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
冲向地球的流星
那就是宇宙
of a place we call the Universe.
它们已经毁灭了恐龙
They've already wiped out the dinosaurs
和许多其他物种
and many other species.
并且它们必定会再次袭击
And there's no doubt they will strike again.
这将是一场远超出圣经中所描述的灾难
It would be a disaster far beyond biblical proportions.
小行星的研究不仅关乎科学
Investigating asteroids isn't just about science.
小行星对人类来说
Asteroids are gonna be one of our
将是最大的难题之一
biggest problems for humanity.
这关乎生死存亡
It's about survival.
所以  我们对小行星越了解
So, the smarter we can get before then,
越能想出解决办法
the more we can figure out,
我们能做些什么呢
can we do anything about it?
为最新的小行星发现做好准备
Get ready for the latest asteroid discoveries
大胆作出前往人类未曾到达之地的计划
and daring new plans to go where no man has gone before.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制&调校:无影  字幕来源:人人影视  招募Q号:76846146
宇
宙
小 行 星 侵 袭
第5季　第6集
2029年
It's the year 2029,
一颗科学家追踪了数十年的
and an asteroid that scientists have been tracking
小行星将在地球附近经过
for decades is passing close to earth.
这颗小行星约为三个足球场宽
The asteroid is about three football fields wide.
命名为阿波非斯
Its name is Apophis,
源于埃及神话中的破坏之神
after the ancient Egyptian God of destruction.
据最新预测显示
According to the latest predictions
阿波非斯并不会在2029年撞击地球
Apophis won't hit earth in 2029,
但是当它经过一个
but as it passes through a seemingly
看似没有特征的空间区域时
nondescript area of space nearby,
整个科学界为之处于高度警戒状态
the world's scientific community goes on high alert.
天文学家计算出
Astronomers have calculated
一个很小的空间区域
a very small region of space
格雷戈·朗丁
加州大学圣克鲁斯分校
如果阿波非斯碰巧经过那个区域
which, if Apophis happens to go through that region,
那它就会在2036年
then it will be set up for a collision
与地球发生碰撞
with earth in 2036.
这个极小的区域
And this very, very tiny region,
直径不到一英里
which is less than a mile across,
仅有几千英尺
just a few thousand feet across,
其被称为锁眼
is called the keyhole.
一个国际航天合作机构
An international cooperative of space agencies
发射一枚火箭接近阿波非斯
launches a rocket to take on Apophis.
目前  你并不想用核武器炸毁它
Now, you don't wanna blow it up with a nuclear weapon.
首先  那需要很多能量
First, that would take a lot of energy,
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
同时还会产生大量的碎片
and it would just produce a huge number of fragments,
它们都将涌向地球
all heading toward the earth.
真正应该做的是给它一点推动力
What you really wanna do is give it a bit of a push
轻微改变它的轨道
that slightly changes its trajectory.
那样的话  就不会发生碰撞
That way, we don't get a collision.
但是这个三千万吨重的太空岩石
But it's possible that the 30 million ton space rock
有可能因为体积庞大
could simply be too massive.
以至碰撞未能使
The collision hasn't knocked
小行星偏离足够的距离
the asteroid far enough off course.
2036年撞击所产生的威力
The impact in 2036 is thousands of times stronger
会是广岛原子弹爆炸的数千倍
than the atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima.
即刻产生的陨石坑
The immediate crater is as wide as
如曼哈顿岛大小
the island of Manhattan.
其将形成一个宽于两英里的陨石坑
It would create a crater over two miles wide.
如果阿波非斯撞击某个城市
If Apophis were to hit a city...
那这个城市就玩完了
Goodbye to that city
周围一百英里的地区也随之毁灭
and the surrounding region for 100 miles.
冲击波  爆炸  狂风大作
From the shock wave, the blast, the winds coming out,
布鲁斯·贝茨
美国行星协会
撞击后的喷出物
from the impact ejecta,
以及进而发生的
and from the massive earthquake equivalent
等效强烈地震
that would occur,
这些都会影响到大部分地区
that would reach out and be felt over huge areas.
阿波非斯最早被发现于2004年
When Apophis was first discovered in 2004,
最初判断的碰撞率大概是1/37
the initial odds of an impact were about 1 in 37.
但近年来  碰撞率不断下降
But those odds have been dropping over the years,
因为科学家们仔细观测了它的运行轨道
as scientists have obtained a better look at its path.
可以做这样一个类比
You can make the analogy
唐·耶蒙斯
喷气推进实验室
确定轨道的过程
that the orbit determination process
和预测飓风差不多
is similar to predicting hurricanes.
当飓风初形成时
When a hurricane first starts out,
你是不可能预测出精确路线的
you don't know exactly where it's going to go.
在接下来的一两周
And as you get more and more data
不断获得更多的数据
in the next week or two,
才能完善预测结果
then you can refine your predictions.
所以
And so,
这和确定小行星与彗星的运行轨道极为相似
it's very much like that with asteroids and comets.
观测的时间越长
The more observations you get over time,
就越清楚
the better you know
目标未来的运转轨道
where the object will be in the future.
这就是为什么现在预测的与地球相撞的几率
That's why today's odds of an earth impact,
仅为1/250000
only 1 in 250,000
这与之前1/37的结果
are so much slimmer than the original
相差甚远
1 in 37 prediction.
即使阿波非斯没有撞击地球
But even if Apophis doesn't hit earth,
此惨剧必会在未来上演
there's no doubt that something else eventually will.
航天机构非常重视
It's a disaster that space agencies
这一灾难
take very seriously.
2010年7月
In July 2010,
美国宇航局顾问团提议创建
a NASA advisory panel recommended the creation
一个行星防御办公室以处理
of a planetary defense office to figure out
所有向地球而来的小行星的
how to detect and deflect any asteroids
探测和转向问题
heading our way.
我们都清楚
We know for a fact that
一颗小行星将会撞击地球
an asteroid is going to impact the earth
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
在将来的一万年以内的某个时刻
sometime in the next one to 10,000 years,
小行星的体积还很大
a big one.
值得思考的是  撞击何时发生
And it's a good question as to when it's gonna happen
那时我们是否能对此有所准备呢
and are we gonna be ready for it when it does?
海边的游乐场不是一个
A seaside amusement park is an unlikely place
演示小行星和彗星
to demonstrate how asteroids and comets
撞击地球的理想之地
speed around our corner of the universe.
但是这里的游戏设施却能够充分演示
But an arcade attraction here actually reveals a lot
这些致命天体的撞击过程
about these deadly objects.
我们的太阳系有些像射击场
Our solar system is kind of like a shooting gallery.
小行星和彗星偶尔撞击
Asteroids and comets can occasionally hit
行星和卫星
planets and moons,
撞击后产生巨大的陨石坑
creating gigantic impact craters.
目标体积越大
Now, the bigger objects present
射击可选范围也越大
a larger cross-sectional area.
所以  很容易就能打中
So, they're easier to hit.
在这种情况下
In this case,
我需要击中这些靶心
I actually have to hit these little bull's eyes,
它们都是一样大小
which are all about the same size.
设想一下那边的男士代表木星
But imagine that the man over there is Jupiter.
很大  这个花栗鼠代表地球
He's big, and the chipmunk might be the earth,
小一些
smaller.
这些蚂蚁则代表月球  更小一些
And these ants might be our moon, even smaller.
因此木星很容易就被击中
So Jupiter is pretty easy to hit.
而地球  这个花栗鼠  难打些
Earth, the chipmunk, is harder to hit.
因为可射击范围小一些
It's a smaller cross-sectional area.
打中了
There it goes.
地球被击中了
Earth was hit.
蚂蚁很小
The ants are small.
所以  更难打中了
So, they're even harder to hit.
大部分小行星未能击中目标
Most of the asteroids miss.
只有偶然情况下才能击中
Only occasionally do they hit.
然而不同于射击场  无论是子弹
But unlike the shooting gallery where the bullets,
还是这样的一束光
or in this case, flashes of light
都是沿直线运动的
always travel in straight lines,
小行星和彗星  却是以弧线运动到目标的
asteroids and comets curve toward their targets.
木星通过其地心引力将小行星和彗星
Jupiter tends to draw in the asteroids and comets
吸引过来
through its gravity.
就好比
So, it's kind of like,
我原本的射击目标是在那里
if I start with my aim way over there,
木星吸引枪杆  使之朝向它
Jupiter pulls the barrel of the rifle toward it,
让我直接命中
giving me a direct hit.
由于地球比木星小很多
Since earth is much less massive than Jupiter,
由其引力吸引的小行星数量较少
its lower gravity doesn't draw in as many asteroids
月球的引力只相当于地球引力的一小部分
and the moon, with only a fraction of earth's gravity
所吸引的小行星少之又少
attracts even fewer.
但是月球表面的许多月坑显示
But as the moon's crater pocked surface illustrates,
长时间的非经常性小行星的撞击
infrequent asteroid impacts over a long period of time
依然意味着巨大的破坏性
still means plenty of destruction.
木星吸引彗星和小行星的能力
Jupiter's ability to pull in comets and asteroids
近年来不断显现
has been on display a lot recently.
1994年
In 1994,
苏梅克-列维9号彗星的碎片击中木星
the Shoemaker-Levy 9 comet fragments pounded Jupiter.
科学家以为这种大型撞击
Scientists thought this kind of large impact
相当罕见
was a rare event,
实属百年一遇
something to be seen once every few hundred years.
但是很快  另一颗彗星或小行星
But then, another comet or asteroid hit
于2009年七月再次撞击
in July 2009.
这次撞击导致产生了一块大黑斑
It created a large dark spot
和相当于地球大小的火球
and a fireball as large as the earth.
两个不同的木星撞击者
Seeing two different sets of impactors hitting Jupiter
撞击时间只间隔了15年
only 15 years apart gives some indication that
这说明太阳系可能比我们想象的还要活跃
the solar system might even be busier than we thought.
2010年六月  一名业余天文爱好者拍到
Then, in June 2010, a third object hit Jupiter,
第三颗物体
with an amateur astronomer
撞击木星时的画面
capturing the moment of impact.
这会不会迫使科学家们
Would this force scientists
改变现有的学术定论
to change their estimates and acknowledge
认为木星被大型物体撞击的频率
that Jupiter is hit by large objects
远多于百年一次呢
much more often than every few hundred years?
我认为这其实跟我们原有的观点
I think that there's not necessarily many more
并无多少不同
than we thought before,
因为
and that's because,
2009年撞击的物体
the object that hit in 2009 was smaller
体积小于苏梅克-列维9号彗星
than comet Shoemaker-Levy 9.
并且那些运行着的小型个体的数量
And there are many, many more small objects flying
远远多于大型个体
around there than there are large objects.
但是不论是关于大型还是小型的
But information about any type of impact,
撞击信息
large or small,
总归是有用处的
is always helpful.
若要了解威胁地球的撞击
To understand the impact hazard on earth,
我们必须得了解
we need to understand
小行星的数量与其运行轨道
the asteroid population, their orbit.
因此  每一条信息都是至关重要的
So, every piece of information,
包括去了解撞击木星的时间跨度
even if it's understanding how often they hit Jupiter
或者是其他天体
or out in the Jupiter region,
对于我们掌握太阳系小型物体的
contributes to our understanding of
整体数量和判断
the overall population of objects in the solar system
我们对撞击地球的关注度也至关重要
and how concerned we need to be about earth impact.
小行星数量的主要来源
The major source of that population
是火星和木星之间的小行星带
is the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter.
在此区域内木星的引力
That's where the strong gravitational pull of Jupiter
阻止了上百万的小型石块
has kept millions of smaller rocks
形成新的行星
from becoming another planet.
但是一切并非到此为止
But that's not the whole story.
那么我们认为小行星就是来自
So we think of asteroids as those things
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
火星和木星之间小行星带的物体
that just live in the belt between Mars and Jupiter,
因为它们中的大部分
because that's historically where most of them
最初都在那里被发现
were found at first.
但是事实上  有这么一些小行星
But in fact, there are asteroids
与木星毫并不相干
that travel way out past Jupiter.
有些与太阳近在咫尺
There are asteroids that come close to the sun,
还有些与地球近在咫尺
asteroids that come close to earth.
最大的一颗便是宽600公里的谷神星
The largest asteroid is 600-mile-wide Ceres,
相当于从华盛顿到芝加哥的距离
which would stretch from Washington D.C. to Chicago.
它大到足以
It's so large that it makes up
占据小行星带的1/3体积
about 1/3 of the total mass in the asteroid belt.
如若此等物体来袭
An impact from something like that
对地球上的生物而言
would be very bad news
必是灭顶之灾
for every living creature on earth.
它的破坏力将是
It's about 100 times bigger than
奇求鲁布陨石撞击的一百倍
the impactor that caused the Chicxulub impact,
而正是此者导致地球上
which resulted in the extinction of
70%的物种消失和恐龙灭绝
70% of the species on earth and dinosaurs.
因此  乍看之下似乎很糟糕的样子
So, right off the bat, it seems like a bad thing.
但是事实上要更加糟糕
But it's a really, really bad thing.
它是远糟于圣经故事中的灾难的浩劫
It would be a disaster far beyond biblical proportions.
它将会导致
It would create a crater
一个差不多和美国一样大的坑痕
nearly as big as the United States.
与此同时
But while it was doing that,
还会喷发蔓延全球的熔岩
it would spew out molten material around the globe,
和满世界的超音风暴
create supersonic winds around the globe.
不堪入目
It would be ugly.
幸运的是  谷神星围绕着太阳运转稳定
Luckily, Ceres is in a stable orbit around the sun,
而大型小行星又很容易定位和跟踪
and large asteroids are easy to spot and track.
如果一颗宽度大于一公里的小行星
We'd probably have decades of warning,
可能撞击地球的话
if an asteroid larger than a mile wide
我们将有几十年的警告期
had a chance of hitting earth.
但是从最近的信息看来
But the smaller ones present a tougher challenge,
小型个体才是更大的挑战
as the latest information shows.
小型行星的数量远多于大型行星
There's far more small ones than large ones.
因此  假若要列举
So, if you say the objects that are
直径大于等于一千米或者六七百米的小行星
one kilometer or 2/3 of a mile in diameter or larger,
我们认为大概有940个
we think there's about940 of those,
并且已经发现了其中的86%
and we've discovered 86% of the population.
若把视线转向较小的小行星
If you move to smaller objects,
比如说是直径100米以上的
say 100 meters and larger,
我们认为大概有五万个
we think there's about 50,000 of those
并且已经发现其中的10%
and we've discovered 10%.
若看更小的小行星
And if you move to smaller still objects,
30米左右的
30 meter and larger-sized objects,
我们认为大概有两百万个
we think there's about two million of those objects
而我们已经发现的还不到1%
and we've discovered much less than 1%.
未来十年会出现更好的望远镜
Better telescopes coming online over the next decade
将为天文学家发现
will allow astronomers to identify
更多的小行星提供可能
many more asteroids of all sizes.
但是一颗宽为30米或者100英尺的小行星
But a 30 meter or 100-foot-wide asteroid on
可能在临近撞击地球之前
a collision course with earth might not be discovered
才会被发现
until just before it hits.
尽管尺寸不大
Something that size
却仍可能是致命一击
could still pack a devastating punch.
地球上布满了过去小行星
The earth is covered with evidence of past collisions
撞击的证据
with asteroids.
如今科学家们废寝忘食的工作
And today's scientists are working feverishly
希望能预测出将来的发展
to figure out what's coming next.
他们知道过去无数的太空来客
They know that enormous space rocks have wiped out
已经洗劫了地球的大部分生命
most life on the planet in the past.
好消息是它们来得并不频繁
The good news is that they don't hit very often.
布鲁斯·贝茨
行星协会
百万甚至数千百万年
It's measured in many millions
才会来袭
or tens of millions of years.
而且它们的大块头
And they're big enough that through our observations
足以让我们通过观察来定位
we know where those objects are.
所以  我们有很久的准备和警戒时间
So, we'd have long, long lead time and warning.
事实上更大的威胁
It's actually the smaller ones
是小型行星
that are the bigger risk,
因为其频率更高而且不易于发现
as they happen more often and they're harder to find.
想像一下其中一颗小行星
Imagine that one of these smaller asteroids
正向城市俯冲
is streaking toward a city.
而直到迫在眉睫的时候
It may not be spotted
人们才发觉它
until just a few hours before impact,
来不及疏散人群
leaving little time for evacuation
更没有机会将它扼杀在宇宙中
and no chance to try and deflect it in space.
假设撞击宽度为100英尺
If it's about 100 feet wide on impact,
那将产生
then it will hit with the energy of
五百万吨核爆炸的能量
a five megaton nuclear blast,
是当年在长岛爆炸的原子弹能量的
400 times more powerful than the atomic bomb
四百倍
dropped on Hiroshima.
撞击地球的时候  将会带来极大的破坏
When it hits the earth, it can cause a lot of damage,
因为由此产生的
because the crater that's produced is
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
陨石坑大小往往是
typically 10 or 20 times
撞击物体宽度的10到20倍
the width of the incoming object.
因此陨石坑将达到几千英尺直径
So, that would be a thousand or a few thousand feet.
并且周圈的大片地域
And many miles surrounding the impact region
也会受到喷射出来的碎片的影响
are affected by all the debris that gets ejected.
这些东西将倾盆落在你身上
You'd have all this stuff raining down upon you.
然而  即使小行星的撞击地点
But even if the asteroid hit
是在城市的几百公里之外
hundreds of miles from the city,
仍然会把那里人们的生活
it could still create chaos
搞得糟糕不堪
for the millions of people living there.
如果小行星撞击的是大型农业区
The food supply for the city residents
那么居民食品供应
could be drastically altered
将会极度短缺
if the asteroid hit a major agricultural area nearby.
不仅仅是人类
Not only would all of the humans
面临死亡的威胁
there be very likely dead,
但是这能够烧焦
but it would sear
数百平方英里的植被
hundreds of square miles of the growing lands.
它能摧毁所有种植的庄稼
It would destroy all the current crops
并且导致大面积的土地
and it would render
在很长一段时间内成为废地
the area pretty unusable for quite a period of time.
而一些体积更小的小行星
And smaller asteroids
甚至根本不用撞击地面
don't even need to impact the ground
就能造成大面积的破坏
to cause widespread destruction.
1908年  在西伯利亚通古斯卡河附近
In 1908, an air burst
由于一颗小行星在大气层中爆炸
from an asteroid that broke apart in the atmosphere,
从而导致了
leveled an estimated 80 million trees
数百平方英里内
over hundreds of square miles,
八千万棵树木的死亡
near the Tunguska river in Siberia.
当一颗小行星或是彗星袭击地球时
When an asteroid or a comet is coming toward the earth,
首先碰到的是大气层
it first encounters the atmosphere
大气层会挤压它
and it squeezes it,
强烈的压缩所产生的压力
it compresses it, and that pressure
会使得小行星或者彗星发生爆炸
causes the asteroid or comet to explode.
如此的爆炸会将其
That explosion then spreads the energy
所带来的能量释放到
over a vast region
位于大气层之下的很大一片区域
of the ground below it.
所以在大气层中的
So, these atmospheric air bursts
爆炸也非常的危险
are very dangerous as well.
但是陨石所产生的破坏性
But the rock that caused all of that destruction
或许要比我们开始想象的那样小
may have been even smaller than first thought.
当它撞击大气层时
When it hit the atmosphere,
若是把通古斯卡看做一个物体
the Tunguska object
那么这个物体或许仅仅只有几十码宽
may have been only a few dozens of yards across,
而不是像起初估计的那样
instead of hundreds of yards,
有数百码宽
as originally estimated.
在一开始  这看起来是件好事
At first, it may seem like a good thing,
因为通古斯卡远比我们想象的要小
Tunguska smaller than we thought.
但事实上这对于
But it's actually a bad thing
我们日后的预测是件坏事
for our future predictions,
因为小型小行星
because there are more smaller objects
比大型小行星要多
than larger ones.
所以如果一个小的天体
So if a small object
就能产生如此大的破坏
can cause that much damage,
那么意味着
then that means
大型天体撞击的频率
it's going to happen more often than
比原先想象的要更快
if it were a big object.
我们或许每几百年里
We may have that impactor
就会受到次撞击
every very few hundred years,
而不是几千年
instead of every few thousand years.
体积小于
At the really small end of the scale,
一百英尺的小型太空石块
below about 100 feet,
通常被称为流星体
space rocks are often known as meteoroids
而不是小行星
instead of asteroids.
流星雨就是由于流星体
Shooting stars are caused by meteoroids
在大气层中燃烧形成的
burning up in the atmosphere.
流星雨不时的会被业余相机捕捉到
They're sometimes captured by amateur cameras,
伴随着一些小石块撞击到地面
with some small chunks hitting the ground
或是汽车和建筑物上
or even cars or buildings.
事实上  地球的大气层
In fact, the earth's atmosphere is
受到外太空物体撞击的频繁度远远
pelted with objects from outer space far more often
超过人们的了解
than most people realize.
我现在来到这个工作当中的采石场
I'm here at this active rock quarry,
在这巨大的碎石堆旁
next to this big pile
因为这就是冲撞地球的
of crushed rock, because this is about
物体的总量
the amount of stuff,
包括灰尘  沙  石子
the amount of dust and sand and pebbles
它们每天都在撞击着地球的大气层
that hit the earth's atmosphere every day,
大约有一百吨之多
about 100 tons.
这足够装满
That's enough to fill about
六至七辆自卸卡车
six or seven of these dump trucks.
这儿  有个篮球大小的石头
Now, down here, we've got a basketball-sized rock.
平均每天有两个这样大小的石头
On average, about two of these
猛烈撞击着地球的大气层
slam into the earth's atmosphere every single day.
接下来是小汽车大小的物体
Next is the small car-sized object.
想象一下一个有这堆石头大小的物体
Imagine this pile of rocks as one object slamming
猛烈撞击到地球的大气层
into the earth's atmosphere,
物体和一辆小汽车的大小一样
about the size of a small car.
这样的撞击每两个星期就发生一次
This happens about once every two weeks.
但是即使是这样庞大的
But even something this big is
物体也将在到达
probably gonna burn up completely
地球表面之前被完全燃尽
before reaching the earth's surface.
对于一个典型的
For a typical object
物体撞击地球大气层来说
hitting the earth's atmosphere,
这个物体的直径至少要在一百英尺
it needs to be at least 100 feet in diameter
才能够对地球表面造成严重的破坏
to actually do serious damage to the surface.
然而直径为一百英尺的石头非常巨大
Now, 100 feet is a really big rock.
这段距离大约是从
That's like going from the front of
卡车的前端一直到
the dump truck over there
那边的橘色交通锥的长度
all the way to that orange cone over there.
在这幅光谱图的另一末端处
At the other end of the spectrum is earth's largest
是地球最大的一个陨石坑
confirmed impact crater,
陨石坑位于南非的弗里德堡
located in Vredefort, South Africa.
陨石坑可延伸长达一百八十多英里
It stretches more than 180 miles across,
二十亿年前的撞击
and drastically changed the ancient earth,
使地球发生了巨变
when it hit about two billion years ago.
这会将物质又反送回太空
It would have sent a sheet of material into space,
而这物质将再返地球
which would then have come back
并对地球产生影响
and impacted on the earth,
比如点燃任何可燃物
ignited fires if there was anything to burn.
并且气候效应也会受到影响
And the climactic effects from that impact
而且有可能持续数十年
would have lasted for decades.
海洋可能会被完全酸化
The oceans would have been completely acidified.
将会有成千上万吨的浓烟
There would have been tons and tons of soot
上升至大气层中
up in the atmosphere.
这也是我们非常
And so that is something that we really
不愿意见到的
would not want to see happen.
在地球处于原始生物时代时
For the primitive life on earth at the time,
由于地球受到撞击导致大多物种灭绝
it was a major extinction event,
撞击中出现的陨石坑的大小
with a crater more than 1 1/2 times larger than
是使恐龙灭绝的陨石坑的一点五倍
the one that wiped out the dinosaurs.
南非陨石坑直到二十世纪九十年代
The South African crater wasn't discovered
才被发现
until the 1990s,
在过去的二十亿年里
since most of its features had eroded
陨石坑的面貌大部分都被侵蚀了
in the last two billion years.
但是太空中所拍的照片揭示了它的存在
But photos from space revealed its existence.
在陨石坑中央突起的山丘在最初
A hilly region in the center of the deep crater initially
被科学家认为是
had scientists thinking that there'd been
火山活动区域
volcanic activity in the area.
事实上
But it's actually
这被称作中央反弹峰
what's known as a central rebound peak,
其主要特征是
a distinctive feature for craters
宽度为一百英里以上
about 100 miles wide or larger.
正如你接到一个从高空坠落下来的
As you get to larger sizes,
大体积的物体
the energy of the impactor is so high,
当它到达之时
that when it comes in,
事实上石头本身是没有力度可言的
the rock essentially acts like it has no strength.
而你所得到的是譬如
Then what you get is something very much like
当你把石子扔进水中
when you drop a pebble in water,
你会看到四周扩散的波纹
and you see that rebound peak
当水重新填补之后
as the water fills in,
水面又恢复平静
comes back up.
但是这是岩石
But since it is rock,
产生波纹时的状态凝固了下来
it then solidifies.
我们将会在月球或者太阳系的其他地方
And we see lots of these central peaks
看到很多这样的中央峰
on the moon and elsewhere in the solar system.
很多大型小行星撞击过地球
But there are other large asteroids that have hit
甚至比六千五百万年前
much more recently, even more recently than
那颗将恐龙灭绝的
the dinosaur-killing asteroid from
小行星撞击还要近
65 million years ago.
三千万年之后
30 million years later,
另一颗大型小行星
another massive asteroid
撞击到美国东海岸
pummeled the east coast of America,
也因此  形成了现在的切萨皮克湾
and helped form, what is now Chesapeake bay.
我们可以看到在整个东海岸
We see evidence of debris from that impact
都还有那次撞击残留下来的碎片
all the way up and down the eastern seaboard.
一路沿着新泽西和纽约
All the way up to new Jersey and New York,
一直到最南端
and comparable on the south end of it.
一个宽达五十五英里的
The 55-mile-wide crater was
陨石坑深藏在了水下
hidden from view underwater,
直到上世纪九十年代
until oil exploration confirmed
在勘探石油的时候才被证实存在
its existence in the 1990s.
若小行星撞击离岸不远的海域
And since the asteroid hit just offshore,
这将引发巨大的海啸
it created a massive Tsunami.
一些人觉得这些海浪可能高达
Some say that the waves could have been
十或者二十甚至三十英里
10, 20, maybe even 30 miles high.
这是非常巨大的海浪
That's a big wave.
阿巴拉契亚山脉也就只有
The Appalachian mountains are
几千英尺高而已
only a few thousand feet high.
所以尽管水浪在涌入内陆时
So even though a lot of the wave was diminished
水量已经减少了  但仍不可小视
as it went inland, that's a lot of water.
这些水能够越过
And it could well have flooded over
阿巴拉契亚山脉
the Appalachians and into
然后进入俄亥俄河谷地区
what we now think of as the Ohio river valley.
如果那样的撞击发生在今天
And if that same impact happened today,
那么东海岸将从此改变
the east coast would never be the same again.
一颗小行星撞击所产生的
An asteroid attack has
力量足以瞬间结束
the power to instantly kill
数百万人的生命
millions of people.
最强的冲击波还能造成全球性的大灾难
The largest impacts can also cause global catastrophes,
危机人类的生存
threatening the very existence of mankind.
那就是为什么小行星的研究是科学家们
That's why the study of asteroids is one of science's
最优先的课题之一
highest priorities.
三千五百万年前  一个巨大的小行星撞击了
35 million years ago, an enormous asteroid slammed
美国的东海岸
into America's east coast.
五十五英里宽的陨石坑直到不久前才
The 55-mile-wide crater was hidden until recently,
在切萨皮克湾的水底被发现
under Chesapeake bay.
撞击的结果是毁灭性的
Its effects were devastating.
但如果同样的撞击发生在今天会怎么样呢
But what if that same impact happened today?
它会通过引起一系列的海啸  冲击波和热效应
It would wipe out the east coast essentially through
从而将东海岸彻底毁灭
a combination of tsunamis, blast waves, thermal effects,
布鲁斯·贝茨
美国行星协会
它还会抛出大量的喷射物
and it would also throw out huge amounts of ejecta
它们会传播到很远的地方
that would spread to great distances,
引起森林火灾
igniting additional forest fires.
数百万的人会在撞击时马上死亡
It would be millions of people instantaneously killed
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
或者在撞击后不久死去
or shortly after the impact.
但它还会引起更进一步的后果
But it would have farther-reaching consequences too,
因为整个地区的
because of the overriding disruption
生态平衡都被打破了
throughout the entire region:
农业  通信业
Farming, communications,
当然我们的中央政府
certainly our center of our government
也在东海岸
is on the east coast.
但最近发现的古生物遗迹表明
But according to recently uncovered fossil records,
一英里宽的切萨皮克湾小行星
the one-mile-wide Chesapeake bay asteroid
对地球造成的影响
didn't seem to have the same global effects
比不上那颗六英里宽
as the massive extinctions triggered
导致恐龙大范围灭绝的小行星
by the 6-mile asteroid that killed the dinosaurs.
三千多万年前
The impact that created
造成切萨皮克湾的撞击
the Chesapeake bay structure
格雷戈·朗丁
加州大学圣克鲁兹分校
威力非常强大
more than 30 million years ago was enormous,
但它仅仅只是六千五百万年前
but it was still only a small fraction of the energy
在尤卡坦半岛撞击释放的能量的
that was released during the impact in the Yucatan,
一小部分
65 million years ago.
撞击刚好提供了引起
The impact was right on the threshold of
全球性影响的能量
providing truly global effects,
刚好可以造成
right on the threshold of
一次大范围的生物灭绝
what's required to make a mass extinction occur.
由于这种毁灭性的力量
Because of that destructive power,
了解我们要面对的问题很重要
it's crucial to know exactly what we're dealing with.
那就意味着近距离和亲身观察小行星
And that means getting up close and personal.
2001年  美国宇航局名为"接近"的任务
In 2001, the NASA mission named "Near"
预定目标是在小行星伊洛斯上空盘旋
was supposed to just orbit the asteroid, Eros.
但当它一到达那里
But once it had got there
并完成任务时
and it completed its mission objectives,
我们决定
the decision was made,
着陆到小行星上
let's try to land this thing.
那真是太有意思了
Which is really, really fun.
有点像老一套的探索方式
It's kind of old-fashioned exploration.
"嘿  过去试试吧"
"Hey, go ahead and give it a try."
于是他们这么做了
So, they did.
从接近到着陆的图像
The images from the approach and the landing
给了科学家们
gave scientists a much more detailed look
一些关于小行星
at the surface of an asteroid
从未有过的详细信息
than they'd ever had before,
还带来了一些意外收获
with some unexpected results.
从这些小行星得到的其中一个惊喜
One of the surprises looking at these small bodies
就是它们也有地质构造
is that they have geology.
它有地壳构造  而且看起来
It had tectonic features, and looks like
吉姆·贝尔
康奈尔大学
它的表面有山崩和侵蚀发生
it had landslides and erosion happening on its surface,
到处都是撞击的陨石坑和巨石
and impact craters all over it and boulders everywhere.
有人想象那种场景  当一颗小的小行星
And one imagines the scenario where a little asteroid
运行并撞到一颗大点的小行星后碎裂了
comes along and hits a bigger asteroid, crashes into it,
引出了一大堆残骸
digs up a whole bunch of debris,
慢慢下降到小行星表面
and that slowly settles down.
而这些巨石就这样散布到了
And these boulders are just spread across
整个小行星表面
the entire surface.
"接近"号探测器甚至
The "Near" spacecraft even
在着陆后向地球
transmitted information back to earth
传回信息达大约两周之久
for about two weeks while on the surface.
但它与地球的无线电通信已经失效
But it has lost its radio link with the earth,
唐·耶蒙斯
喷气推进实验室
所以现在  它只是静静地坐在那里
and so now, it's simply sitting there,
待上数百万年
mute for millions of years.
日本外太空署的
The asteroid explorer Hayabusa,
"早房"号小行星探测器
of the Japan aerospace exploration agency,
最近又有新的突破
recently one-upped near.
它是第一个着陆到小行星表面
It's the first spacecraft to ever land on an asteroid
然后返回地球的探测器
and then return to earth.
它在运行了四十亿英里后
It arrived in June 2010
于2010年六月返回
after a four billion mile round trip.
按计划  大多数航天器
As planned, most of the spacecraft
在地球大气层被烧毁
burned up in the earth's atmosphere,
但带回样本的太空舱
but the sample return capsule
成功着陆在澳大利亚内陆
successfully landed in the outback of Australia.
即使到现在
Even today,
还不清楚是否存在微小的样本
it's still unclear if minute samples are present.
对太空舱仔细的检查还在继续
The careful examination of the capsule is continuing.
这是个漫长的过程  但人们很乐观
It's a long process, but people are optimistic
相信我们能从第一个返回地球的
that we're going to get great data out
小行星样本中提取出有用的信息
of the first asteroid samples returned to earth.
对于一个地球化学家来说
To a geochemist,
就算样品只有几微克
a couple of micrograms of material
已经足够进行详细的化学和矿物学分析
is plenty to do some detailed chemistry and mineralogy
以及一些综合分析
and compositional work.
在"早房"号返回前
Even before Hayabusa returned,
另一个小行星探测任务  已经开始了
another asteroid mission was already underway.
三  二  点火
3, 2, engine ignition.
发射
And liftoff...
2007年美国宇航局"黎明"号探测器
After a 2007 launch, the NASA Dawn spacecraft
发射前往火星和木星之间小行星带
is on its way to two of the largest asteroids
最大的两颗小行星
in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter.
"黎明"号将于2011年抵达
Dawn will arrive at
直径320英里的灶神星
320-mile-wide Vesta in 2011,
环绕其运行一年
orbit for a year,
然后于2015年抵达直径六百英里的谷神星
then reach 600-mile-wide Ceres in 2015.
你无法发现两颗小行星的
You couldn't find two asteroids more different
不同之处
from one another.
谷神星之前被认为相对潮湿
Ceres is thought to be relatively wet,
可能表面有冰覆盖
perhaps subsurface ices,
而另一颗灶神星
and the other one, Vesta,
被认为正好相反
is thought to be the opposite.
完全没有氢氧化物
It's completely lacking in hydrated minerals
或者冰
or water ice.
它一生都在被如此大程度地加热
It's been heated over its lifetime to such an extent
以至于被认为是分层的
that it's thought to be layered:
有类似地球的分层的表面
A surface layer, a mantle, and a core
有地幔和地核
much like the earth.
所有这些任务揭示出小行星的
All of these missions are revealing that asteroids
组成比我们之前认为的
are made from a much wider assortment of materials
更加多元化
than we first realized.
小行星有非常多的种类
There's a huge variety in asteroids.
有些富含铁和镍
Some of them are iron rich or nickel rich,
很像这个哑铃
very much like this iron dumbbell.
另一些很类似这个地球上的岩石
Others are very similar to this earthbound rock.
它们是石质的
They're stony.
岩石构成的
They're rocky.
还有其他的由铁类和岩石类
Still others are a combination between the iron type
组合成的类型
and the stony type.
我们还发现了像碎石堆一样的外来物
We've also got exotic things like rubble piles,
就像这一堆砂砾构成
which are like having this handful of gravel,
但全部都由引力束缚
but if it all were gravitationally bound
在大的小行星表面成为一种类型
in a big asteroid kind of a form.
我们还发现了外太空的彗星残骸
We also have ex-comets.
彗星残骸没有了它们的表面的冰覆盖
And ex-comets have gotten rid of all their ices,
留给我们这种很好的粒状的物质
and we're left with this fine grain material,
感觉像是多孔的绒球
held in a very porous type of fluff ball.
但小行星除了它们的组成外
But asteroids are surprising us in other ways
还有其他方面令我们吃惊
besides their composition.
"伽利略"号探测器在前往木星的途中
The Galileo mission on its way to Jupiter
经过了一颗叫艾达的小行星并且发现
went past an asteroid called Ida and discovered
它有颗小的卫星就是艾卫
that it had a little tiny moon called Dactyl.
这真是太令人意外了
This was a big surprise.
现在  我们知道这不仅仅是个巧合
And now, we see that that's not so rare an incident.
小行星确实会有它们自己的卫星
Asteroids do come with their own moons,
有时候会有几颗
sometimes several moons.
我们也明白了许多小行星
We're also learning that a lot of asteroids
是以双星
are traveling in pairs as binaries,
甚至三星的状态存在
or even with three of them.
这是很非常新鲜的观察结果
And that's a very new set of observations
是需要了解的新事物
and new thing to understand.
理解小行星是如何成群的
Knowing how asteroids are grouped
它们是如何构成的
and what they're made of
不仅是科学感兴趣的问题
is more than a matter of scientific interest.
想象在未来  一颗巨大的
Imagine in the future, that an enormous,
致命的小行星向地球袭来
deadly asteroid is speeding towards earth.
如果人类还想生存
It needs to be deflected
就必须让它偏离轨道
if mankind is going to survive.
但是如果我们不知道
But if we don't know exactly
小行星的具体构成
what the asteroid is made of,
那么要挽救地球
then the effort to save the planet
就非常困难
could go horribly wrong.
小行星撞击的破坏性
An asteroid impact can unleash more destruction
胜过任何一种自然灾害
than just about any other kind of natural disaster.
但它也是少数一种我们能够阻止的
But it's also one of the few types of nature's fury
大自然灾难
that we may be able to prevent.
想象在未来  一颗巨大的校行星
Imagine in the future that a huge asteroid
以每小时七万英里的速度冲向地球
is racing towards earth at 70,000 miles per hour.
全世界的宇航局联合起来
International space agencies have banded together
发射了一枚火箭想挽救人类
and launched a rocket in an effort to save mankind.
致胜的诀窍就是了解敌人
The trick is to understand the enemy.
小行星是金属质的吗
Is it made of solid iron?
还是碎岩石
Is it made of shattered rock?
又或者是由碎石
Is it made of a rubble pile,
或是个曾是彗星的绒球
an ex-cometary fluff ball?
因为如果你用一艘宇宙飞船
Because if you hit a slab of solid iron
唐·耶蒙斯
喷气推进实验室
撞击一块固态铁
with a spacecraft,
跟撞击一个绒球的反应
it's going to react far differently than an object
是截然不同的
that is a fluff ball.
据了解  小行星是个碎石堆
The asteroid turns out to be a rubble pile.
它足够柔软
It's soft enough to
可以吸收火箭几乎全部的撞击力
mostly absorb the impact of the rocket
仍然会保持原轨道撞向地球
and to stay on course to collide with earth.
体积也足够大
It's also large enough
不会在大气层燃尽
that it doesn't burn up in the atmosphere.
它击中了地球
It hits,
永远改变了地球上的生命
and forever changes life on our planet.
如果我们不尽可能多地了解
This is the price we could pay if we don't learn
太阳系中各种各样的小行星
as much as possible about the variety of asteroids
这就会是代价
in our solar system.
但是至少对于大型小行星接近地球
But at least with large asteroids,
我们会有数十年的
we should have years or decades of
警告时间
warning about their approach.
对于彗星甚至是巨大的彗星
With comets, even enormous ones,
警告时间将以月来衡量
the warning time will be measured in months.
为什么
Why?
那就是乔治亚州亚特兰大的克莱顿·艾尔.
That's what Clayton L. in Atlanta, Georgia
想问宇宙的问题
wanted to ask the universe.
他给我们的电子邮件中写道
So, he e-mailed us:
为什么彗星撞击地球比小行星撞击地球的
"Why would there be "So much less warning time" before
警告时间少那么多
an earth impact for a comet compared to an asteroid?"
问得好  克莱顿
Good question, Clayton.
我们想知道什么时候会有东西撞上我们
We'd love to know when something might hit us.
因为小行星离我们很近
It turns out that asteroids are so nearby,
我们可以精确追踪它们的轨道
that we can track their orbits precisely.
那就意味着我们可以精确地预测
That means we can make accurate predictions
未来的几十甚至几百年中
of where they will be,
它们会在哪里
tens or even hundreds of years in advance.
那意味着我们也许可以
That means we might be able to deflect them
在它们撞上地球之前改变它们的轨道
before they hit the earth.
现在  一颗彗星
Now, a comet
从太阳系中飞来
comes in from the outer depths of the solar system,
还没亮到能让我们看见
and doesn't become bright enough to see,
直到也许半年
until it's maybe six months
或一年后就会撞上地球
or a year away from hitting us.
所以我们很难得到警告
So, we have very little warning.
幸运的是  绝大部分有可能
Fortunately, most of the things that potentially
撞击地球的是小行星  不是彗星
could hit the earth are asteroids, not comets,
而且我们能非常精确地追踪它们
And we can track the asteroids pretty accurately.
宇宙难题
事实是未来的某一时刻
The fact that asteroids have a much greater chance
小行星有很大机会破坏地球上的生命
of destroying life on earth sometime in the future
所以发射无人探测器去研究它们
is one of the main reasons why studying them
是如此重要
with unmanned missions is so important.
但是在2010年四月  美国总统奥巴马
But in April 2010, U.S. President, Barack Obama
宣布了一个更大的挑战
announced an even bigger challenge.
在2025年
By 2025,
我们希望新型宇宙飞船能够长途旅行
we expect new spacecraft designed for long journeys
使我们可以送人上天
to allow us to begin the first ever crewed missions
进入比月球还要遥远的外太空中
beyond the moon into deep space.
所以我们将史上首次
So we'll start by sending astronauts to an asteroid
送宇航员登上小行星
for the first time in history.
以我的经验  作为大学教师
In my experience as a college teacher,
年轻一代  他们想走得更远
the younger generations, they wanna go beyond.
吉姆·贝尔
康奈尔大学
是的  你知道我的祖父母上过月球
Yeah, my grandparents went to the moon, you know.
我们要超越他们
Let's go beyond.
因此这就是总统的信息中
And so, that was an inspiring part of
鼓舞人心的部分
the president's message,
美国宇航局需要
that we need to get NASA back
重新投身到外太空事业中
into the business of deep space.
载人飞船登上小行星
A manned mission to an asteroid will be very different
跟过去登上月球是大不相同的
from moon missions of the past.
某些方面更容易
In some ways, it will be easier,
但另一些方面  要难得多
and in other ways, much harder.
无论宇航员要去哪颗小行星
Whichever asteroid the astronauts visit,
距离比去月球都要远得多
will likely be a lot farther from earth than the moon.
所以行程可能持续几个月
So the journey will probably last for months,
而去月球只要八天时间
instead of the eight days it takes to get to the moon.
但是整个旅程需要的燃料
But the round trip will actually use less fuel
将少于登月计划
than a lunar landing mission.
你在月球的时候
When you go to the moon,
需要对付身体
you're dealing with a body
明显的重力
with significant gravity of its own.
你将不得不全程使用更多的燃料
You're having to use more fuel
来减慢速度
to safely slow yourself down
并安全着陆
and descend all the way to the surface.
当前往一颗低引力的小行星的时候
When you head to an asteroid with very low gravity,
布鲁斯·贝茨
美国行星协会
即使你走了更远的路才到达那里
even though you're going farther to get there,
你却不必为
you aren't having to expend
类似着陆之类的事情
nearly as much fuel for things
花费那么多的燃料
like getting to the surface.
当你离开小行星
It also takes less propulsion ability
启程回地球的时候
when you leave the asteroid
也需要更少的推进力
to head back to earth.
但是在小行星表面着陆
But landing on an asteroid's surface
跟登陆月球
will be much more challenging
相比是更大的挑战
than setting down on the moon.
相比登陆  它更像入港
It's more like docking than it is landing,
但是你还是有些重力
but you do have some gravity.
所以你得对付这一点点重力
So you have to deal with having a little bit of gravity.
你必须让自己精确抛锚
But you have to deal with actually anchoring yourself,
并抓住不放
holding on.
当你在有地球六分之一重力的月球上时
You don't have to hold on when you're in the 1/6
你不需要抓住不放
earth's gravity of the moon.
对于宇航员来说探索
Exploring a small rotating asteroid
一个小型的旋转中的小行星
will also be much harder for astronauts
比在月球上跳跃行走更难得多
than hopping around on the moon.
它更像太空漫步
It'll be more similar to a space walk.
你对上下的感觉被破坏了
Your sense of up and down is sort of screwed up
格雷戈·朗丁
加利福尼亚大学圣克鲁斯分校
你在小行星上走动的时候
and you have to be very careful
必须很小心
when you walk around on an asteroid,
因为那里的重力非常小
because the gravity of the asteroid is so weak,
轻轻一跳就可以
a good jump can send you into
把你送入它的环绕轨道
an orbit around the asteroid
甚至让你以逃逸速度
or even send you out at escape velocity
完全脱离这颗行星
and escape from the asteroid completely.
所以你探险的时候
So you have to make sure that you're tethered down,
必须确保自己在可控范围
when you're exploring.
但是"漫游者"已经成功
But since Rovers have already proved
探索了其他世界
to be so successful at exploring other worlds.
有没有足够的理由
is there a strong reason
要送宇航员登上小行星呢
to send astronauts to an asteroid?
宇航员  探险家
Astronauts, explorers,
公众都对太空很有兴趣
the public interested in space
渴望亲眼
yearn to see what it's like in person
看见它的模样
through real human eyes
那一天离我们不远了
and that day is coming.
机器人可以在太空探索中
Robots can do a lot and have done a lot
大显身手  并已功绩显赫
in space exploration.
劳拉·丹利
格林菲斯天文台
但人类才是最好的地质学家
But there is no better geologist than a human being.
作为一个探索小行星的地质学家
To be a geologist exploring an asteroid and being able
要能识别特殊地貌的历史
to recognize the history of a particular region,
观测几种常见的地质结构
looking at familiar types of geological formations,
你知道自己该做什么
you know just what you wanna do:
你知道该采集这块石头作为样本
you wanna go sample that rock,
而另一块则不合适
you don't wanna go sample that rock.
小行星中蕴藏的资源
Asteroids are also important because of the resources
也使它们备受关注
they might contain.
时间跳至2050年  一队宇航员驾驶着飞船
The year is 2050, and a crew of astronauts
刚刚在一颗小行星上着陆
has just landed their spacecraft on an asteroid.
他们不是为探索而来
They're not here to explore...
而只是路过补给
this is merely a pit stop.
可在这岩石遍布的小世界里
But what types of precious resources
能藏着什么珍贵的资源呢
could this small rocky world possibly contain?
所有生物都将灭绝于一次小行星撞击
An asteroid attack can wipe out entire species,
人类也不例外
including humans.
但是人们没有听天由命
But instead of accepting that fate,
科学家们正努力充分研究它们
scientists are trying to learn enough about them
以阻止灾难的发生
to prevent disaster.
那些没朝着地球行进的小行星
And asteroids that aren't headed towards earth
也许会对我们大有益处
may even turn out to be helpful.
我们之所以要造访并研究小行星
One of the reasons to visit asteroids
吉姆·贝尔
康奈尔大学
原因之一就是
and to study them is that
它们也许拥有一些对未来的探索者
they may have some resources that could be useful
大有裨益的资源
to future human explorers.
其中最重要的就是
And among the most important of those would
冰和水
be ice, water.
人们需要用冰来取水饮用  维持生命
People are going to need ice to live and drink
还可以用在其它实际方面
and use in a practical sense.
时间再次跳至2050年  一队前往火星的人员
The year is 2050, and a crew on its way to Mars
刚刚在一颗小行星上着落
has just stopped at an asteroid
补给水与其它物资
for water and other supplies.
水中的氧气可以被分离出来
The oxygen in the water can be separated
填充队员的氧气罐
to refill the crew's breathing tanks.
但是这座岩制补给站
But there's even more that this rocky supply station
可以提供更多
has to offer.
可以想象到的是  有了先进的技术
It's conceivable that with advanced technology,
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
我们可以抵达那些小行星  分解水分子
we could go to those asteroids, break down the water,
分解得到的氢和氧可以用作飞船的燃料
and use the hydrogen and oxygen as fuel
使它飞得更远
to take spacecraft even farther.
那里甚至有一些地球上稀缺的
And there may even be priceless materials
极其珍贵的物质
to bring back to earth,
这些元素对于高科技的实现至关重要
elements so rare and critical to high-tech success
因此它们可能成为未来战争的导火索
that they could be the cause of future wars.
有些小行星蕴含着铂  钛等
Some asteroids have platinum and titanium
稀土元素  电子产品的方方面面
and rare earth elements that are important
都离不开它们
in many aspects of electronics,
这些元素之所以被称为稀土元素
which are called rare earth elements for a reason,
是因为它们在地球上很罕见
because they're rare on the earth.
而在某些种小行星上
They might not be so rare
它们也许常见得多
in certain kinds of asteroids.
但是研究小行星最主要的原因
But the most important reason to investigate asteroids
还是因为它们能瞬间
remains their ability to instantly
带走无数人的性命
kill millions of people
或灭绝全人类
or wipe out the human race altogether.
为了削弱这种威胁
To counter this threat,
NASA在2009年12月 启动了"明智"计划
NASA launched the "Wise" Mission in December 2009.
广域红外探测器
The wide field infrared survey explorer
已经发现了
has already found
25000颗小行星和12多颗彗星
25,000 asteroids and more than a dozen comets
这些用以前的可见光无法侦测到
that were too dark to find using visible light.
它在不停观测我们的太阳系
It's actually looking all around our solar system,
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
希望能覆盖99%的天空
hopefully to look at 99% of the sky
并努力定位更多
and try and map more
我们之前没能发现的
of these near-earth objects, these asteroids
近地物体和小行星
that we haven't found in the past.
希望这能帮助我们弄清
And hopefully, that will help us in understanding
是否存在一些短期内可能与地球
if there are any that are in near-term
发生碰撞的天体
collision courses with the earth.
尽管头版新闻不经常报道
And even though it doesn't usually make front page news,
但已有许多小行星
there are already plenty of asteroids
近距离经过了地球
that pass close to earth.
在2010年4月  一颗70英尺宽的小行星
In April 2010, a 70-foot-wide asteroid passed
从距离地球220000英里的地方经过
within 220,000 miles of earth,
这要小于地球
which is closer than the distance
到月亮的距离
from the earth to the moon.
在这的几个月前
And a few months before that,
一颗23英尺宽的小行星更加接近地球
a 23-foot-wide asteroid came much closer.
在2009年的冬天  也就是11月的时候
In the winter of 2009, in November,
一颗小行星
there was an asteroid
简直是与地球擦肩而过
that passed so close to the earth,
它离地球最近时
it was only 8,000-9,000 miles
仅仅相隔8000到9000英里
away at its closest approach.
直到它离我们咫尺之遥时
And we didn't know about that
我们才意识到这一点
until it got fairly close.
这段距离相当于
That's about the same distance as flying
从洛杉矶飞至印度孟买的航程
from Los Angeles to Mumbai, India.
回到1972年  在临近怀俄明州大提顿的地方
And back in 1972, a tourist's camera
一名旅客的摄像机
near the grand Tetons in Wyoming
捕捉到一个类似大小物体
captured a much closer pass
以近得多的距离擦过地球
by a similar-sized object.
1972年的小行星几乎就撞上了地球
The 1972 event was about as close as
当然最后没发生碰撞
you can get to a collision without actually colliding.
按照它行进的路线  本该撞上地球的
On its way in, it was going to collide with the earth,
但由于大气压力的作用
but it skipped off of the atmosphere
它掠过了大气层
due to the pressure of the air,
就像打水漂一样
like a pebble being skipped off
卵石掠过湖面
of the surface of a lake.
那可真是次亲密接触
That was a really close call.
随后的2008年10月
Then, in October 2008, a small and seemingly
在非洲苏丹的偏远地区
uneventful impact occurred in a remote part
发生了一次看似无关痛痒的冲撞
of the African country of Sudan.
可它象征了人类在预测小行星撞击领域
But it actually represented a giant step forward
跨出的一大步
in the science of predicting asteroid impacts.
人们发现了一颗小行星
A small asteroid was discovered
并预测它会在第二天
and it was predicted to land
在苏丹落地  最后的确如此
in Sudan the next day, and it did.
这是我们第一次
Now, this is the first case we have of an object
观测到一个物体  并预测出它落地的
that was discovered and then predicted to land
详尽时间与地点
at a particular time and place.
事实上  随后人们在沙漠中
And in fact, fragments of this object were later found
发现了它的碎片
over the desert.
可是
But that was only
这次只有一天预警的撞击不过是米粒之珠
a small impact with a single day's notice.
如今  我们到底有没有能力去
Today, the jury is still out on whether we'll be able
识别并避免一次毁灭地球的灾难
to identify and deflect something that could inflict
还尚无定论
catastrophic damage on earth.
科学家们相信
Scientists believe there are still millions
无数未知的小行星仍飘荡在宇宙中
of unidentified asteroids out there
它们可能摧毁一座城市
capable of destroying a city...
或更糟
or worse.
我们能找出
Will we be able to figure out
那些不速之客吗
which ones will cross our path?
我们能阻止它们
And will we be able to prevent them from
撞上地球吗
slamming into earth?
我们承受不起如此之高的风险
The stakes couldn't possibly be any higher.
对小行星的每一点新发现
Each new discovery in the world of asteroids
都不仅仅象征着科技的进步
isn't just a scientific advance,
更意味着人类幸存下去的概率有可能
but an opportunity to increase the survival chances
因此提升
of mankind.